# **Dickson Kipketer**

# Fullstack Software Engineer

**Phone:** 0722307764

**Address:** P.O. Box 28198, Nairobi 00200

**Website:** https://dkklimo.github.io/portfolio/

Email: dkklimo@gmail.com

I am a Passionate Fullstack Software Engineer having an experience of building Web applications with Javascript/VueJS/ReactJS/NodeJS/php/Laravel and some other cool libraries and Framworks.

As a software engineer, I enjoy using my obsessive attention to detail, my unequivocal love for making things that change the world. That is why i like to make things that make difference. Please Click HERE to check my portfolio

### Competent Skills

- Laravel
- AWS re/start
- NodeJs
- ExpressJs
- MongoDB
- MySQL
- Wordpress
- Bootstrap CSS
- ReactJS
- Jquery
- Javascript
- HTML5 & CSS

#### Administartive Skills

- Freshdesk Helpdesk
- Freshsales CRM
- Odoo ERP

# EXPERIENCE

# **Molars Dental Practice**

September 2021 - To date

## Web Developer

#### **Brand management**

- Develop a virtually interesting and eye-catching website that existing and prospective customers will be interested in navigating
- Ensure user-friendly designs on the website that encourage traffic of both advanced users as well as beginners
- · Support the writing of content that encourages traffic and enhances customer interest in the company and its produdts
- Proactively and creatively ensure the company's website functionaly on all browsers thus enhancing the flow of traffic.
- Maintain the responsiveness of the website to the various incorporated commands and links thus enhancing customer interest and satisfaction

### **System Management**

- write well designed, testable, efficient code by using best software development practices
- create a website layout/user interface by using standard HTML/CSS practices, creatively ensuring enhanced customer satisfaction by ensuring clarity and visibility
- Integrate data from different backend services and databases
- Gather and refine concepts, specifications,s and requirements based on technical needs
- Create and maintain software documentation
- Be responsible for maintaining, expanding, and scaling the company website
- Advise team members on emerging technologies and apply in company operation.
- Match visual design intent to support capturing target audience effectively
- conduct keyword research and use SEO guidelines to optimize content
- Measure web traffic content.

# Studygate

- 1. Help Students Understand Data structures and algorithms.
- 2. Help them write Algorithms.
- 3. Help develop web application with Full Stack Javascript
- 4. Teach Database Fundamentals
- 5. Help write SQL scripts in MySQL Database
- 6. Help with HTML5, CSS, and Python programming languages Assignments

# **Annay Agencies Softwares Co. Ltd**

May 2017 - August 2017

## Web Developer Trainee

3- months industrial Attachment with Annay Agencies Softwares Co. Ltd as a junior web Developer. I was doing web application development, WordPress website design and development, graphic design, SEO and google analytics.

## **EDUCATION**

# **Karatina University**

August 2014- November 2018

Bachelor of Science Computer Science

# **Chebiemit Boys High School**

February 2010- November 2013

High School

#### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

- Website Design and Development: WordPress, HTML5, CSS, Bootstrap CSS,jQuery and Javascript
- Install, customize, and manage ERPNext.
- Set up, configure, customize and manage FreshDesk Helpdesk and Freshsales CRM.
- a good memory of how software and operating systems work
- excellent listening and questioning skills, combined with the ability to interact confidently with clients to establish what the problem is and explain the solution
- the ability to work well in a team
- problem-solving skills
- a strong customer focus
- the ability to prioritize my workload
- attention to detail.

#### LANGUAGES

English (Full Professional proficiency ), Swahili (Native ),

### RECOMMENDATIONS

# Joseph Mutai December 2019

CEO, Annay Agencies Software.

Email:jkkenzie@gmail.com Phone No: 0720 832 300

# Ms. Joan Wakasa Murumba

November 2018

Ag. HoD Computer Science and Informatics, KARATINA UNIVERSITY

Email: jwakasal4@gmail.com Phone No: 0722 776462